Venus
Radonitsa Colony
(Coronal)
What is it that people desire?
Within the ordinary lives
we lived until yesterday...
When suddenly, an unexpected door of fate
appears before us...
(Impact sound)
(Explosion)
(Wistario)
Why our town… why…!?
(Girl crying)
(Demnar)
This is...
It appears to be
a Mobile Suit attack…
(Wistario)
A Mobile Suit!?
(Demnar)
Young master! This way!
(Wistario)
Right!
(Demnar)
The basic controls are the same as
the one you usually use...
the Hloekk Graze.
However, the Ahab Reactor output
is more than double.
We will support you from here as well,
but please be careful.
(Wistario)
Thanks.
Hm?
Gramps, what does “Hajiroboshi” mean?
(Demnar)
That is this machine’s pet name.
(Wistario)
I see.
Then…
Let’s go, Hajiroboshi.
(Coronal)
When a light...
capable of changing your life,
your future, everything...
appears before you…
I’ll never forgive you
for scarring my town!
(Coronal)
My name is Coronal Xhosa.
Do you possess a Ring?
A Ring?
Ah...
You mean…
this?
(Coronal)
Heh…
Graturatio.
Congratulations.
You have earned the right
to participate in the “Urdr-Hunt.”
(Coronal)
Guide and navigator,
Coronal Xhosa.
One who opens doors
and leads others onward…
However...
looking back now, perhaps the door of fate
had opened before me as well...
just as equally…
I doubt I will ever forget
that day.
Yes.
The day I met
Wistario Afam.
♪～
46.2
Mobile Suit Gundam: Iron-Blooded Orphans
Urdr-Hunt – Path of the Little Challenger
♪ The signal that it had begun
♪ I can’t remember it at all
♪ Before I knew it,
I had already been running forever
♪ So much it makes me want to cry
♪ I realized people
are never truly equal
♪ Reality is cruel
♪ Beaten down,
aching with unbearable loneliness
♪ Even so,
my legs still keep moving
♪ So no matter how far
♪ I’ll go even farther
♪ Even if this should become
♪ a night with no dawn
♪ Even if the thing I wished for
that day
♪ was more than I deserved
♪ it moves me
beyond all control
♪ It keeps pushing me onward,
again and again
～♪
(Coronal)
Urdr-Hunt Memorandum.
Today, by order
of my master “N”...
the commencement of the Urdr-Hunt
has been declared.
The Urdr-Hunt is...
a race in which those who possess
the qualifying Rings...
travel between designated points
to collect specific data.
The grand prize is…
100 billion Melia.
An amount capable of...
completely changing the life
of whoever obtains it.
(Alert sound)
Huh?
(Renzie) Ah!
(Coronal)
Dreams left unfulfilled…
ideals… desires…
A vast fortune capable of pulling
all of them into reality.
If that is the case…
then perhaps it is inevitable
that the struggle surrounding it...
would become one fought
with lives at stake.
Haa…
83.2
Small Transport Ship Erda-Maru II
(Wistario)
How is it?
Did you figure out
what’s written on the Ring?
It appears to be
some sort of code…
Unfortunately,
I cannot decipher it.
I see…
If it’s a ship from
the Calamity War era...
maybe the data is connected
to that time period…
(Coronal)
A message has arrived
from my master “N.”
(Wistario)
What!?
(Applause)
Graturatio.
You have cleared
the first mission of the Urdr-Hunt...
successfully.
(Wistario)
Huh? That was it?
(Coronal)
Within the Urdr-Hunt,
an encounter with a rival means
a struggle for one another’s lives.
In a sense,
that is the truth.
However…
(598)
Who the hell are you calling pirates!?
(Wistario)
You attacked a merchant ship
with Mobile Suits...
no matter how you look at it,
that makes you pirates!
(598)
Don’t lump us in
with some cheap small-timers!
Someday, we’re gonna become
the next Tekkadan!
Tekkadan!?
Did you just say Tekkadan!?
Yeah, I did!
We’re gonna become
the next Tekkadan!
Hmph!
(Wistario)
Don’t screw around with me!
When did they ever
make a name for themselves
by pulling pirate crap like this!?
Guh…
(Coronal)
There were times when,
after clashing with everything at stake...
strange bonds would be born
between people.
(598)
Nngh… guh…
I’m fine…
(144 and others)
Waaaaah!
(Kimbal)
Who the hell are you!?
(Impact sound)
(Kimbal)
Whoa!
Man, there’s just something
about you guys that pisses me off!
(598)
Guess I owe you one.
Thanks.
(Wistario)
It’s fine.
I just stuck my nose into it on my own.
(598)
Heh. Fair enough.
(Wistario)
So what are you gonna do now?
If you’ve got nowhere to go,
I could hire you over on Venus.
Venus?
With the prize money
from the Urdr-Hunt...
I’m gonna buy back
my home colony, Radonitsa!
Huh? Wait… what?
Buy it back?
A colony!?
(Wistario)
Yeah!
Right now, that beautiful planet
only gets prisoners sent there...
but I’m gonna turn it into a place...
people from everywhere
actually want to visit.
And for that,
I’m gonna need a lot of help.
Mm…
You’re already acting
like you’ve won the Urdr-Hunt.
(Wistario)
Hm?
(598)
Sorry, but…
I don’t think it’s gonna be
that easy.
(Wistario)
Then I guess
that can’t be helped.
Yeah!
Next time we meet,
you’re my rival.
I won’t hold back,
so be ready, Wistario Afam!
Same to you, 598.
Yeah.
See ya!
(Coronal)
598 and his companions.
Deceived by the pirate Kimbal
and used as his underlings...
they followed Wistario’s advice...
and reclaimed ownership
of their Rings.
They then officially joined
the Urdr-Hunt.
And through all of that,
another important meeting took place…
(Eating sounds)
Who’s there!?
Ah...
Hm?
You were on Kimbal’s ship…
(Swallowing)
(Cature)
Don’t call me “you.”
I’m Cature.
Cature Inoshee.
(Muffled voice)
Hold on, let me finish eating this first.
(Clapping)
(Coronal)
Cature, who had been held captive
as cargo aboard the pirate ship...
became a new member
of Wistario’s crew.
The fact that he gained
a female companion his own age...
was something
that delighted me as well.
172.2
Falk Family Private Vessel
Cocoon Nidhoggr
And then,
there was one more…
(Renzie)
Guh…
Huh!? What is that!?
(Alert sound)
(Andy)
What the hell are these things!?
Gwah!
Mr. Cyclase!
What the hell is going on!?
(Cyclase)
The Cocoon’s automated defense system.
Huh!?
(Cyclase)
Once activated,
it deploys a massive number of unmanned craft...
a system from the Calamity War era
designed to eliminate enemies completely.
Though apparently,
it can’t distinguish targets very well,
so it attacks everything in sight.
What!? You activated this thing!?
(Cyclase)
I told you
I’d send reinforcements, didn’t I?
(Renzie)
Ah!
(Cyclase)
And let me warn you,
trying to stop the system is pointless.
Damn it…
So we were expendable from the start!?
(Andy)
More of them are coming!
Boss! We’ll buy you some time!
(Bito)
You make sure you get out alive!
You idiots…
Stop it…
(Andy)
We already decided this.
(Impact sound)
(Andy)
Guh…
We’re not gonna keep
getting rescued forever.
Next time, we’re gonna save you
and finally look cool doing it!
(Bito)
You still gotta build...
the paradise
you promised us!
That was the deal!
Cut it out… you idiots…
Uooooooh!
(Bito)
It’s the Renzie Squad!
Don’t underestimate us!
(Bito)
Gah!
Ugh!
Gah…
(Explosion)
Bito!
(Renzie)
Stop it!
Bito! Andy!
Boss…
we told you to run…
Guh…
How could I run
and leave you behind!?
Heh… you can’t do that…
That was the promise… right…?
(Andy)
Boss… you can’t die in…
Ah…
a… place… like…
Andy!
(Explosion)
Cyclase, you bastard!
(Andy) Boss…
(Renzie) Guh!
(Andy) We’re counting on you…
(Renzie) Ghh!
(Andy)
For me… and Bito… too…
(Impact sound)
(Renzie) Gah!
Ugh…
Cyclase…
I won’t… forgive…
(Wistario)
Hey!
Are you okay!?
(Coronal)
Though he belonged
to a rival organization...
he was betrayed by his superior
and lost his comrades...
Renzie Dablisco.
I’m not dropping out
of the Urdr-Hunt.
I still haven’t achieved my dream.
The Urdr-Hunt
is my greatest chance.
You mean that whole
“building a nation” thing?
You’re willing to sacrifice your friends
for your own dream!?
It’s not just my dream.
It’s everyone’s dream!
Right now, the Radonitsa Colony
doesn’t belong to any economic bloc.
That means the people of Venus
don’t even have IDs.
In other words,
they’re treated like nobodies.
If we had our own nation,
we’d finally have a place to belong.
We could proudly stand tall
as “the people of Venus.”
It’s a dream meant
to make everyone happy.
And with the Urdr-Hunt prize money,
I’m gonna make it happen.
(Coronal)
In order to fulfill his own dream
and avenge his fallen comrades...
Renzie decided to travel
alongside Wistario.
(Incoming transmission)
(Subordinate)
Boss.
(Tamami)
What is it?
(Subordinate)
We’ve located their ship.
(Tamami)
Got it.
I’m heading over now.
(Palstai)
Ah!
Who the hell are you?
(Tamami)
Name’s Tamami Rakow.
I’m the boss
of the Rakow Pirate Crew.
(598)
I’m 598 of the Foundlings.
What does a pirate want with us?
We’ve got proof you brats attacked
a Teiwaz-registered cargo ship.
I’m here to make you answer for it.
(Coronal)
Tamami Rakow,
one of the Ring holders...
is the leader of the Rakow Pirate Crew
under the Turbines umbrella.
Just spare the ship
and the Mobile Suits.
This place is our home,
and we need them to survive.
We’ll pay compensation.
And whatever we can’t cover now,
we’ll find a way to repay later.
(Tamami)
Anyone can say that.
Then I’ll prove
it’s not just talk.
What, you planning to chop off a finger?
(598)
An entire arm.
Huh?
Right here, right now,
I’ll cut this arm off.
(Palstai) Ah!
(Wistario) 598!?
(Renzie)
Hey! You…
(598)
Then believe my words.
Fine.
(Tamami)
Let’s see you do it.
(Palstai) Like hell we will…!
(Impact sound)
(Alert sound)
(Wistario)
What now?
(Rohm)
Ha-ha!
See that, Aiko!?
(Rohm)
This great Rohm Zahn
is taking down every Ring holder at once!
(Aiko)
Yeah, yeah.
You’re amazing, big bro.
Seriously though,
we could’ve waited until after
they finished fighting each other…
(Rohm)
Did you say something?
(Aiko)
Big bro, you’re the best!
(Coronal)
I was on edge worrying
about the fate of 598’s arm, but...
after being attacked by a common enemy
and fighting back-to-back together...
they managed
to reconcile for the moment.
From then on,
598 and the others would work under Tamami...
and learn the ways of business from her.
Alright then,
who’s next!?
Ah!
(Rohm)
Behold!
The Gorgeous Pink and…
the Gorgeous Silver…
(Rohm & Aiko)
Brother Attack!
Gwaaaaaah!
(Rohm)
Aiko! Uwah!
What...
did you say!?
(Rohm) Damn it all!
303.2
Bauduin Family Orbital Satellite
Sleipnir Periphery
(Coronal)
Not every Urdr-Hunt participant...
is a seasoned fighter
capable of piloting a Mobile Suit.
Kozo Mendo is a...
treasure hunter researching
the Calamity War said to have occurred...
roughly 300 years ago.
(Mendo) Yeah.
That's right, young man.
(Wistario) Hm?
(Mendo) About your
Gundam Frame...
Hajiroboshi?
Yeah...
There shouldn't be
any Gundam Frame...
with a name like that.
Huh?
(Mendo)
What was your name again?
Wistario Afam.
Try to remember it this time.
Are you sure that's your real name?
Huh?
(Mendo)
Once you learn Hajiroboshi's true name...
you may no longer be able
to remain who you are now.
(Coronal)
According to Mr. Mendo...
every point indicated by the rings...
is managed by one of the Seven Stars'
seven great houses...
and consists of ruins or relics
dating back to the Calamity War.
The Calamity War...
We Navigators are...
beings tasked with guiding
ring-bearing participants...
under the orders of our master "N,"
the organizer of the Urdr-Hunt...
However...
we have not been told anything
about the Urdr-Hunt's true purpose...
or the nature of the data being collected.
The connection between the Urdr-Hunt,
the Seven Stars, and the Calamity War...
Could it all really be true?
Still, there have certainly been events...
that make it hard to dismiss it all
as mere speculation...
(Iok) The Calamity War...
(Iok) A mass-murder weapon
from the Calamity War... you say!?
And something like that
is inside territory overseen by House Kujan!?
(Iok's Subordinate) Um...
(Iok) How could I possibly allow...
my precious subordinates
to remain exposed to such danger!?
Suspend the investigation immediately!
Inform the field team
to withdraw at once!
Until I personally arrive
to conduct the investigation...
the colony is to be sealed off!
(Gjallarhorn Soldier A)
Hey.
We've got orders from Lord Iok
to pull out immediately.
(Gjallarhorn Soldier B)
Huh? Withdraw?
What about this thing?
We're just leaving it here?
(Gjallarhorn Soldier A) Can't be helped.
Those are the orders.
(Footsteps)
(Cyclase) Well then...
guess it's about time
I got back to work.
(Cyclase)
It was fun talking with you.
Yeah. Same here.
Heh...
Goodbye.
(Ring glowing sound)
(Cyclase) Hm?
(Spreading light sound)
(Gjallarhorn Soldier A) Get back!
(Wistario) That ring...
You're an Urdr-Hunt participant.
So you're...
I've wanted to meet you
for quite some time.
Wistario Afam.
I was curious what kind of person
could single-handedly...
wipe out Renzie's squad.
But I'm disappointed.
So you're Cyclase!
Turns out you're just some boring brat
lost in his own dreams.
Well then, my business here is done.
So this is goodbye.
(Cyclase) Guh!
(Wistario) Ah!
Damn...
What is this!?
Ah...
(Coronal) Waiting for us
at the fourth point was...
a Mobile Armor.
A weapon of destruction
that triggered the Calamity War...
300 years ago
and nearly drove humanity to extinction.
(598) Boss! Hah!
Ah!
Damn it!
What is this thing!?
Why is it only reacting to Wistario!?
Nngh...
Huh!? What's this!?
Hajiroboshi?
No good... I can't control it...
Guh... uh!
Its power increased!? Ah!
"Marchosias"?
(Coronal) The battle
left us heavily damaged.
To carry out repairs and maintenance,
we decided to temporarily...
return to the Radonitsa Colony
on Venus.
Whoa... This is amazing!
(598) Yeah, it's incredible, but...
Does this really count as a colony?
I've never seen anything like this.
This is my first time seeing
an open-type colony as well.
It's different from both
the surface and closed colonies...
This is definitely something
worth seeing for yourself.
(Cature) It's really amazing...
(Sound of wind)
(Cature) Heheheh...
Ah!
What's this?
This is the best!
Welcome to Radonitsa Colony!
(Coronal)
It really is an incredible sight.
(Cature) Yeah.
It makes me want to stay here forever.
If you want to stay, Cature,
you can stay as long as you like.
(Cature) Huh?
(Wistario) You're welcome here.
Ah...
Of course, you'll have to help with work.
You too, Coronal.
(Coronal) Huh?
Once the Urdr-Hunt is over...
will you go back to that person called "N"?
No, I don't have any such plans...
A navigator's duty...
lasts only until the
Urdr-Hunt comes to an end.
(Wistario) Then...
would you help me even after it's over?
Ah...
Would that really be alright?
(Wistario) Of course.
I want to keep drinking your tea,
Lady Coronal.
Heh...
Gratias.
That makes me very happy.
(Wistario) Right, Cature?
Yeah.
You too, 598 and Renzie!
Once I buy the colony with the prize money...
I told you,
I'm not handing over the prize money!
(Renzie) Am I just an afterthought?
(Wistario) Ahahahaha!
(598)
Quit laughing, damn it! Hey!
(Cature) Yeah...
I hope it can happen.
(Coronal) Hm?
(598) Hey! Wistario!
(Sound of explosion)
(Coronal)
While waiting for instructions
for the next point...
there was some trouble with Gjallarhorn...
over the Mobile Suit
they had been hiding...
(Isurugi) That hits a little close to home.
450.2
Large Planetary Cruiser Saisei
(Coronal) Thanks to Ms. Tamami’s introduction,
598 was able to meet...
the members of the Turbines
and Tekkadan that he admired so much...
And somehow,
the amusing brothers who attacked us repeatedly...
ended up forming
a bond of trust with us...
Though there were occasional little disturbances...
our peaceful days
continued on for a while...
(Aiko) Ugh... Aaah...
Ngh... Ugh... Aaah...
Aaaahhh!
I'm sorry, big bro!
Brotheeer!
Come back, Aiko!
(Rohm) Come baaack!
(Aiko) Big bro!
(Coronal)
The great whirlpool...
that would swallow us all...
(Masked Man)
The name reported by Isurugi...
as the person in charge...
of the Afam facility was...
Wistario Afam.
A coincidence?
Or perhaps...
(Coronal) Meanwhile,
beneath the surface,
the ripples continued to spread little by little.
Ah...
(Renzie)
That's a Gjallarhorn Skipjack-class ship.
First time I've ever seen one.
That crest is?
It's the Issue family's.
Huh? One of the Seven Stars?
Ngh...
(Dexter)
Those bastards even brought out Mobile Suits.
Six... seven...
Ugh, counting them is a pain.
There's no way our forces
can handle an opponent like this.
Guess we've got no choice
but to obey the order to stop...
(Cature) No way...
Absolutely not!
Cature?
I'd rather die than let them catch me...
Ah...
(Sound of door opening)
(Wistario) Cature!
(Sound of incoming transmission)
(Lond)
The ship over there, halt immediately.
If you comply,
we won't resort to force.
We are here concerning...
a woman aboard your ship
named Cature Inoshee.
What!?
(Lond)
We ask that you promptly hand over Lady Cature.
Lady... Cature?
(Demnar)
Why would the Issue family?
(Cature) Ngh... Ahh...
Ngh... Nnnh...
Ah... Ah... Ugh...
Wah! Ah!
Let go of me!
Ah...
(Wistario)
Even if you fight them, you can't win.
(Cature)
Even so, if it's a choice between that and being captured...
I'd rather die!
(Wistario)
So they're really that awful, huh?
Got it.
Leave it to me.
Huh? Wah!
(Wistario)
I'll go in Hajiroboshi.
Wistario...
(Wistario)
Renzie, get ready!
We're breaking through their blockade
and getting out of this sector!
Damn it, guess we've got no choice!
Things are about to get busy.
I'll help with the preparations.
Everyone...
Thank you.
Gah!
(Coronal)
Against such a large force...
we were at an overwhelming disadvantage, but...
Its movements are completely different!
(Masked Man)
Looks like...
I made it in time.
(Lond) Ngh!
Now then, go.
But...
(Renzie) Wistario!
(Coronal)
Thanks to the assistance of a man
calling himself Montag...
we somehow managed to escape.
Tch! It's not over yet!
You bastard!
(Masked Man)
Okina Uroka's ambition...
You've noticed it too, haven't you?
(Lond) What?
(Masked Man) Hmph.
Who the hell was that guy?
(Coronal)
Due to a certain incident on Earth...
it seems the Issue family's heir...
a woman named Carta Issue,
passed away.
The current head of the family is elderly,
with little time remaining.
The Issue family, desperate to choose a successor,
set their sights on...
the family head's illegitimate child...
Lady Cature.
You don't intend to return
to the Issue family, do you, Cature?
(Cature)
Return? That place was never my home!
My mother was a servant
for the Issue family.
After she became pregnant with me...
the man who's supposedly my father
threw her away like a filthy rag!
And now they want to take me back?
I’ll never forgive them!
（Coronal）
Cature...
（Cature）
I don’t want to drag everyone into this...
But!
I understand.
You don’t need to worry.
I’ll never hand Cature over
to those bastards.
（Demnar）
Young master...
Cature is my precious friend...
my family.
I’m not giving my family to anyone.
（ring glowing）
(Wistario）Huh?
(Coronal）Ah!
（Wistario and the others）
Ah!
The ring...
（Coronal）
The ring revealed...
the fifth point.
566.2
Fareed Family Abandoned Battleship
Fenrir
However,
Mr. Wistario...
chose...
to avoid heading there
in order to escape pursuit.
We slipped through
the Issue family's blockade…
570.2
African Union Colony
Under Renovation
dodging pursuers
as we continued to flee, but...
eventually, the moment came...
（Londo）
Unforgivable...
To defile the purity
of the future head of the Issue family...
I will not allow it!
Further negotiations are pointless!
We will recover Lady Cature
by force if necessary!
Eliminate every member
of that ship’s crew!
Yes, sir!
No! Stop!
Wistario Afam!
I’ll warn you one last time.
Hand over Lady Cature peacefully!
No!
Ghh...
Then your comrades will lose their lives!
Are you prepared for that!?
（Wistario）
Of course I’m not!
Don’t lay a hand on my friends!
（Londo）
You brought this upon them!
Lady Cature, or your comrades’ lives...
which will you choose!?
（Wistario）
They’re all my family!
（Coronal）
Cature!
（Wistario）
There’s no way I can choose!
I’ll say it again!
Don’t touch my family!
Fool!
Attention all deployed units!
All personnel, eliminate these people at on...
（Cature）
Stop it!
Cature... Ah!
Nobody move!
（Coronal）
Cature!
（Londo）
La... Lady Cature!
（Wistario）
Cature? What are you...
（Cature）
I...
I’ll go to the Issue family.
So...
please stop.
（Wistario）
What are you saying, Cature?
No! I won’t allow that!
（Cature）
Wistario...
Thank you.
For protecting me
all the way to the very end.
It made me so happy.
Happy enough that
I could die right now...
Ghh...
（Cature）
So...
your turn is over.
Now it’s my turn
to protect you and everyone else.
Because...
that’s what family does, right?
Ngh... ngh!
Heh...
（Wistario）
Cature...
（Coronal）
For the sake of family...
That’s what Cature said as she...
left before our eyes.
All of us shared one wish...
We wanted Cature back!
And for that,
we first had to find where she was.
After gathering information
from various sources, we learned...
that the current Issue family
had split into two factions...
fighting over what should be done
with Cature.
And that the man hired
by the opposing faction...
to eliminate Londo Bron,
who had abducted Cature...
was none other than
that Cyclase Myer.
If we follow...
the ship of Cyclase Myer,
whose location we’ve identified...
then surely,
Cature will be waiting beyond it...
Our course was set.
（Cyclase）
I see.
You certainly have skill.
Your head is mine!
（Tagging）
A little greeting to start us off!
（naval bombardment）
（door opens）
（Coronal）
Can’t sleep?
（Wistario）
Coronal...
Sorry.
（Coronal）
Hm?
（Wistario）
Urdr-Hunt...
Because I ended up
abandoning it partway through
No
I want to help Lady Cature too
we all feel the same
And...
it’s not like we’ve
already lost the Urdr-Hunt
Even after we save Lady Cature,
we can still recover
(Wistario) Yeah, you’re right
So let’s definitely
get Lady Cature back
Yeah, definitely
So...
(Coronal) Huh?
(Wistario)
Until then... Lady Coronal...
I want you to hold onto this ring
Understood
Until we get Lady Cature back,
I will keep it safe
(Wistario) Thanks
Hey, you old guys
Eavesdropping isn’t cool
(Dexter)
Then you should...
just go back to your room already
(Demnar)
You should be resting...
the young master was concerned
I can’t sleep anyway
Ever since I heard
Cyclase is involved...
Andy and Bito...
their faces keep popping into my head
and won’t leave
We’re going to save that girl
You haven’t forgotten that, have you?
Don’t lump me in
with senile old men
Of course I remember
But when I face that guy...
I feel like my urge for revenge
is going to explode
(Demnar) That man’s grudge
is your personal matter
I won’t tell you not to take revenge
Old man...
(Demnar)
I’m sure the young master would say the same
Yeah, he might
(Renzie)
He even saved a guy like me...
and let me board his ship
On top of that, he even makes me help
with his dream...
I really don’t understand him
But if it’s his dream...
I oddly want to see it through myself
But before that...
I want to settle things
with Cyclase
(Demnar) Then go settle it
Just don’t you die
Yeah, I know
(Demnar)
You’re also...
a valuable worker who will carry
the future of Venus
Heh.
More importantly, the young master would grieve.
I ain't planning on dying,
and I ain't planning on letting anyone else die either.
I'm gonna settle everything
I left unfinished here...
and from there on out,
all that's left is moving forward!
Do not ever forget those words.
Like hell we're dying before you geezers!
（Sinister）Hmm~?
Looks like something strange
just came into view.
The only strange thing here
is your face, old man.
Our faces are practically identical.
What is it?
（Sinister）
That's the ship we've been chasing.
We caught up to Cyclase!?
Let's go inform the young master.
What the hell is this place?
（Coronal）
The Issue family's sacred ground...
Ratatoskr.
Apparently it's an old-style power transmission system
that uses Ahab Reactors.
Lond Bron, who took Cature with him...
the forces of Cyclase Myer pursuing him...
and Wistario and his companions
chasing after them in turn...
The final battle is finally at hand!
Hah!
（Thunder rumbling）
（Coronal）Ugh...
That's...
Hey, that light...
（Sinister）Hm? Let's see...
There we go.
（Renzie）A Mobile Suit?
Cyclase is out there too!
He's caught up with Cature and the others.
We're heading out too, Renzie.
（Renzie）
I'm ending this here and now!
（Door opens）
(Coronal）Wistario.
(Wistario）Huh?
Please be careful.
I'll definitely bring Cature back!
Yes!
Young master...
Renzie Dablisco, Asmoday.
Wistario Afam, Hajiroboshi.
(Wistario）Launching!
(Renzie）Let's go!
（Coronal）The reason Lond Bron
came to Ratatoskr...
wasn't just to resupply.
It seems he also came
to obtain...
a Mobile Suit passed down
through the Issue family line.
Ah!
Kyaa!
To draw your bow against this Zagan...
Learn your place!
（Subordinate A）Uwaaah!
Hmph.
（Subordinate B）Ngh! Guh...
Gah!
Kyaaah!
（Warning alarm）
（Wistario）Ah!
So you've come.
（Lond）Wistario Afam.
（Wistario）
So it was you after all.
You're giving Cature back!
（Incoming transmission）
（598）Wistario!
I'll give you a hand!
（Cyclase）Well?
（Batch）We've arrived.
Beginning the operation now.
I'm counting on you.
（Warning alarm）
（Cyclase）Hm! So they've come.
（Cyclase）
We'll deal with these annoying flies.
（Tagging）Okaaay.
Yo. I've been wanting to see you.
（Renzie）Cyclase!
So you're still alive,
Renzie Dablisco.
You're the one bastard I won't forgive!
For Andy and Bito's sake,
I'm taking my revenge right here!
（Lond）I'm still not done!
Guh... Ghk!
Ngh!
(Lond）UOOOOOOHHHH!
(Wistario）Ah!
（598）Wistario!
（Lond）Guh...
I am the one who must protect that person!
Gah...
（598）Is it... over?
No. Not yet.
Hang on, Cature! I'm coming!
Guh... Ah!
（Renzie）
Damn it! Stop darting around!
Quit running away, Cyclase!
Hmph...
It's about time.
（Impact sound）
（Renzie）Ah! What the hell!?
Looks like Batch fulfilled her role.
Well, we are exceptionally capable.
This was your doing!?
（Cyclase）Now then...
the beginning of true freedom.
What's happening!?
(Impact sound)
(Renzie) Grrh!
(Coronal) Kyaah!
Lady Coronal!
Ah!
(Coronal) Ah!
That's...
(Coronal) The ring...
(Palstie)
Is it writing data?
(Mendo) Ratatoskr is
a place tied to the Issue family.
So this really was...
the sixth point.
(Slice)
But why now?
(Pilot) Hurry!
They're catching up to us!
What happened to Captain Lond!?
(Co-pilot)
We can't contact him!
(Cature) Wistario...
(598)
It'll be trouble if they board our ship!
Cature...
(Impact sound)
(Wistario) Ah! What was that!?
(Demnar) An optical weapon?
(Dexter)
Just how big is that thing?
(Slice) Ah!
What in the world is that?
Ah...
What the hell is that!?
It's awakened...
The Mobile Armor...
Hah! What is this thing?
(Sound of incoming transmission)
(Wistario) Hm?
(Demnar) Young master, that thing
is a Mobile Armor!
(Wistario)
A Mobile Armor!? This is?
They're really this huge?
Sorry. A little farewell gift from Cyclase.
What're we gonna do, Wistario!?
Cature's up ahead.
If you're gonna stand in my way...
Then I'll crush you and move on!
(Coronal) A Mobile Armor...
Unlike the wreckage from past battles,
this one was fully intact.
Its destructive power
was overwhelming.
(Impact sound)
(Renzie) Guh!
(Coronal) The other members of the
Urdr-Hunt also rushed in one after another...
and it became a battle for survival...
Ngh! Again!?
(Warning alarm)
(Wistario) Ah!
(Wistario) 598!
Wooooooooooah!
Sorry to keep you waiting!
Drop dead!
(Warning alarm)
(Tamami) Huh!?
Yo, brother!
Sorry to keep ya waiting!
(Wistario) Everyone!
Did we get it?
Ah...
Ngh!
(Tamami) Ah!
(Aiko & Roam) Whoa!
That's...
That's the main body?
Ngh!
Huh?
(Wistario)
This is like back then...
Marcho... sias?
(Coronal)
In the end, the deciding factor was...
once again, the activation of...
Hajiroboshi's mysterious
power-up ability.
Ugh! Ugh! Uuuugh!
Ugh...
Ah!
(598) Amazing...
Hah... Hah... Hah...
Is this...
the end?
Yeah... looks like it.
(Renzie)
Even I can't move anymore...
So you weren't the freedom
I had been searching for either...
Still, well...
(Wistario)
That's right! What about Cature!?
(Coronal) Wistario!
The launch carrying Cature
has been swept away!
At this rate, it'll be pulled
into the lightning storm!
Cature!
Hurry, Wistario!
Wistario...
(Coronal) Lady Cature
(Sinister)
16,000 meters to target!
(Dexter)
Just a little more!
Young master...
Hah! Ngh!
Go!
Wistario!
Ah...
No...
Ngh...
No way...
(Sinister) The launch's signal...
has disappeared...
(Demnar)
We... didn't make it...
Ah...
No! Not yet!
(Demnar and the others) Huh!?
(Signal beeping)
Mm...
Hah!
Cature! Why!?
No matter how dangerous the place was,
you always came after me
So I knew...
I had to return to you, Wistario...
Wistario...
I...
(Wistario) Cature!
Let's be happy together!
(Cature) Yeah!
(Coronal)
Lady Cature came back to us
And once again,
we became one
Phew...
(Knocking)
Yes?
(Door opens)
(Coronal) Lady Cature
What were you doing?
I was rereading
the journal entries I've written.
I see
Hey, want to step outside for a bit?
(Coronal) Heh...
Yes
(Coronal)
What is it that people desire?
Within the ordinary lives
we lived until yesterday...
When suddenly, an unexpected door of fate
appears before us...
Our lives... our futures...
When beyond that door,
we glimpse a light powerful enough
to change everything...
The 100 billion Melia prize
has yet to be claimed.
And yet...
I'm certain that something even more precious
than immeasurable wealth lies here...
The irreplaceable treasure
of the people we meet.
(Coronal) Here...
I planned to return it
once we returned to Venus and settled in.
There hasn't been any reaction
since last time, right?
(Coronal) Correct
However, "N" instructed us
to remain on standby.
A message was sent directly to me
as the navigator...
Then the Urdr-Hunt
is still continuing
Yes. Which is why...
Hm? Wait, me too?
(Coronal) Yes
(Wistario) Cature, hurry up!
We'll win the Urdr-Hunt...
And make our dreams come true!
Yeah
Definitely!
(N) Nadezhda
Have you determined
the location of the final key?
(Nadezhda) Yes, my lord
However, what was revealed
was not coordinates...
But a unique frequency
(N) Just as I thought
Either way...
This will finally bring
the Urdr-Hunt to an end
(Cyclase) So... the time has come...
♪～
～♪
960.2
Mobile Suit Gundam: Iron-Blooded Orphans
10th Anniversary
960.4
Wedge of Interposition
(Mikazuki) Phew...
(Ahab Reactor whirring)
(Shino) Mmm...
(Sniffing)
(Shino) When Barbatos fights,
it smells like money
(Eugene) Tekkadan's gonna get
even bigger now
(Akihiro) Tch, I still think I should've...
(Yukinojo) Don't be stupid.
(Yukinojo) It's because you and Gusion
are standing by...
that Mikazuki can fight so recklessly.
Besides...
(Ride) Whoa...
(Yukinojo) It's already over.
Huh?
Ah!
(Battle sounds)
(Boss) Tch...
(Pilot A)
Damn it, quit darting around!
Hey! Can someone
get behind him?
Ah!
(Pilot A) Stop moving...
(Pilot B) In front! In front!
Ah! Ugh!
(Orga) Finish 'em, Mika!
Ah! Ngh...
(Ride) Alright!
(Shino) Alright!
(Akihiro) Naturally.
(Orga) Well then...
Just as requested,
a two-on-one handicap match.
No complaints now, right?
(Boss) I get it.
Hey!
(Yamagi) Make sure everything's secured!
We'll handle the rest
once we're back!
Tie down the smaller stuff
with belts together!
If we don't hurry,
it'll be morning already!
(Gunshot)
(Pilot A) Gah! Help...
(Ride) That's brutal...
Just because they lost,
they didn't have to kill them.
(Shino) Those guys
were pretty well-known...
in mobile suit combat circles,
weren't they?
(Akihiro) Yeah, but they were
Human Debris.
That's what happens when they lose.
What a rotten world.
Though we're not exactly
much better ourselves.
(Mikazuki) I can still fight.
Maybe you can,
but Barbatos is screaming in pain.
Yamagi! Contact Teiwaz!
Make arrangements to send
this thing to the Saisei...
Not yet!
Not yet.
(Yamagi)
You don't want me to contact them?
(Yukinojo) Hah...
Yeah, leave it be!
That guy...
(Yukinojo)
Can't be helped.
Guess we'll just have them send more weapons again.
(Mikazuki)
Tell them to send something better this time.
(Yukinojo)
Teiwaz got a kick out of...
the combat data from that katana of yours.
That's why they only send those now.
Besides, with Barbatos in its current state...
if you tried swinging around a huge mace,
it'd fall apart.
(Mikazuki) Mm...
(President)
Then please sign here.
(Orga) Mm...
Will this do?
(Employee)
Yes, no problems here.
(Orga) Good.
Then the deal's settled.
Your miners will be working
under our umbrella from now on.
(President)
Tekkadan...
It's great that business is going well, but...
you shouldn't think
this kind of business will last forever.
(Eugene)
Like we need him to tell us that.
Now, now...
Let the losers bark all they want.
Right?
(Orga) Hm?
Mm...
(Atra) Mikazuki!
(Orga) Ah!
(Atra) Want another helping?
(Orga) Ah, sorry. What is it?
(Mikazuki) Yeah.
(Shino) Ah...
(Shino)
Looks like you're pretty busy.
(Orga)
Ah, yeah.
I've got some homework from the young lady...
Ah!
Crap! I'm already late for...
(Atra) Ah, your food!
(Orga) I'll eat later!
(Ride) Hey, Boss!
What?!
(Ride)
Um... there's a hole in your pants.
(Akihiro) In the butt.
(Orga) Ah!
(Atra)
Ah, I can sew it up right away.
Just leave it out for me...
(Orga) No!
It's fine. I'm in a hurry.
(Eugene)
Seriously...
Orga already knows that
without being told.
(Shino)
Yeah, about the hole in his ass?
(Eugene)
The business, idiot! The business!
(Shino)
That it can't keep going like this forever?
(Akihiro)
Orga's working hard
to make sure it does last.
(Shino)
Yeah, hard enough
not to notice the hole in his ass.
(Eugene)
I know that already.
He's our representative...
doing his best
with this unfamiliar business stuff.
(Ride)
Yeah, but if our representative's
walking around with a hole like that...
that's not very cool.
Ah! I know!
I've got a great idea!
(Mikazuki)
A great idea?
(Kudelia)
I'm impressed.
There are still some issues here and there, but...
Mm-hm.
You seem to understand it now.
So you really did read
the materials I gave you.
(Orga)
Hmph.
You're the one...
who told me to read them, young lady.
(Kudelia)
And besides...
(Orga) Hey!
(Kudelia)
You've improved quite a bit.
You were the one who told me...
people would look down on me
if I didn't have a proper signature.
Seriously, why do official contracts
need handwritten signatures anyway?
I'd never even held a pen before.
But now you can write
such a wonderful signature.
(Orga) Mm... Mmm...
(Kudelia)
As expected of the Commander.
Ah, come to think of it,
it's getting pretty late.
(Orga)
Maybe we should grab a bite...
(Knock)
Yeah, come in.
(Yamagi)
Um, Commander...
Everyone said to come to the
cafeteria once you're done here.
(Both)
Hm?
(Orga)
Ah... Ah...
F... For me?
It's a present from all of us.
(Akihiro)
"All of us?"
(Shino) Uh...
(Shino)
C'mon, don't sweat the details.
(Kudelia)
My! What a wonderful suit!
You should try it on, Commander!
Wow...
O... Okay...
(Clothes rustling)
(All)
Ooooh!
(Atra)
You look awesome!
(Kudelia)
It suits you perfectly!
(Yamagi)
You look smart.
(Eugene)
Yeah, seriously.
Fits you perfectly too.
(Mikazuki)
Mm-hm, mm-hm.
(Ride)
You look super strong or something!
(Shino)
Seriously!
(Orga)
This feels really weird.
But... thanks.
(All)
Heh... Hahahaha...
(Eugene)
Hey, Orga,
turn around for us.
(Orga)
Huh? L... Like this?
(Shino)
Bwahahaha!
Looking good, Orga!
(Ride)
So cool, Commander!
(All) Hahahahaha...
(Ride) Woo!
(Atra)
Hey...
Is this how you're supposed
to tie a necktie?
It does feel like
something's off...
Ah... wasn't it like this?
(Orga) Ghk!
(Yamagi) Hey, Shino, idiot...
What are you doing?!
(Orga)
Hey! Ghk...
(Eugene)
Man, that looks awful.
Let me see it.
It suits him.
Yeah. That's Orga's new weapon.
Maybe you need one too.
(Mikazuki)
Hm?
(Akihiro)
You should rely on us sometimes.
Or what?
Are we that unreliable?
Not sure.
Hey... you...
(Ride)
Hey, Boss...
If you're wearing that,
you don't need this anymore, right?
Give it to me!
(Orga) You're still too young for that.
(Ride) Heh... eheh...
Maybe when you get a little bigger.
(Ride) You really mean it?
(Orga) Yeah, I do.
(Orga)
The only one I can trust
with my back on the battlefield is Akihiro.
(Akihiro)
Hmph...
(Footsteps)
(Orga)
So...
So you're finally taking
it to the Saisei, huh?
(Mikazuki)
Akihiro said he'd handle it.
(Orga)
I see.
Well, I've got a new weapon too.
We'll be fine.
(Mikazuki)
Yeah... and...
I've got a few things I want to
say directly to the Teiwaz guys over there.
(Orga)
Got a complaint or something?
I'm sick of that pain in
the ass katana thing.
It looks cool when you use it, though.
But it's useless in group battles...
and more than anything,
it's not enough to clear your path, Orga.
Heh... I see.
(Mikazuki)
To see the place you're aiming for...
I have to keep giving everything I've got.
(Orga)
Yeah.
I'll show you...
All kinds of great things.
For all of you.
(Mikazuki)
Yeah.
♪～
♪ Raise your flag
♪ With all your voice
♪ Shout it out loud with all your voice
♪ One day
♪ Someday somewhere
♪ Dream on as we wander
♪ Under pressure
You are waiting for directions
♪ Going on the road
Without your mind
♪ All misleads they give
Ignoring our decisions
♪ Killing yourself your soul
we have inside
♪ Continue the struggle
and feel like you're discouraged
♪ Rise up again to run to the end
♪ In between
♪ The never ending dream
♪ We can struggle and muzzle
the world before it fades away
♪ Raise your flag
♪ With all your voice
♪ Shout it out loud with all your voice
♪ One day
♪ Someday somewhere
♪ Believing that we will reach that goal
♪ Come on and raise your flag
♪ So just raise your flag
♪ No matter how many times
we feel defeated or lost
♪ As long as we breathe
♪ As long as we carry on
♪ Dream on as we wander
~♪
♪～
Translation, Editing, Re-Timing
Drakanwolf
QA Check
TeknoMonkey
~♪